刺客信条
本字幕由 今晚月色真美 个人制作
仅供练习使用  请勿用于商业用途
余 烬
Sì.
进来
I'm taking Marcelo into town.
我打算带马塞罗到城里去几天
To see Machiavelli's play?
去看马基雅维利的戏剧吗
Ezio, his play closed at three weeks ago.
艾吉奥  他的戏剧三个星期前就结束了
I missed it?
我已经错过了吗
We're visiting your sister.
我们要去拜访一下妹妹
Keep an eye on Flavia, okay?
你照顾好弗拉维亚  好吗
Sì, of course.
放心  我会的
We will be back soon. Ciao, amore mio.
我们很快回来  再见  亲爱的
A più tardi. Be safe!
路上注意安全  亲爱的
Flavia, tesoro, stay where I can see you.
弗拉维亚  别走太远
Leave her alone!
放开我女儿
Lei gentile, papa.
她没有恶意的  爸爸
Go inside, Flavia.
进屋去 弗拉维亚
I do not know what else to say.
我不知道该说些什么
I'm sorry. I do not want any part of this.
对不起  我不想卷进你们的是非
I want to understand.
我想知道
Understand what?
想知道什么
How to lead, to rebuilt my order.
如何重新建立我领导的队伍
No! For me, that's over, finito.
不  对我来说那种生活已经结束了
Now I think you should go.
我认为你该走了
Ezio, she has come a long way.
艾吉奥  她可是大老远来到这的
Shao Yun, did they say that right?
邵云  是这样称呼的吗
Would you stay for supper?
要不要留下来吃晚饭
Grazie.
谢谢
Good! We have a spare bedroom.
太好了  我们正好有空出的卧室
You are welcome to stay a few nights.
你可以留宿几晚
Are you Okay?
你还好吗
I can not seem to leave my past behind me.
我好像还是没有甩掉过去的生活
I started to disactive my life so late, Sofia.
我到了这把年纪才开始过上安定的日子  索菲亚
I know I would not have enough time to do everything.
我知道自己没有足够的时间去完成一切
Now I worry that I do not have enough time to do anything.
而现在  我恐怕已经什么都做不成了
Yun!
云
Shao Yun!
邵云
Get out!
你给我出去
The wind, it opened the door.
是风把门打开了
Fuori!
快出去
Sorry.
对不起
I was wrong.
我错了
Sì. I think you need to go.
是的  我觉得你该走了
My name is Ezio Auditore.
我的名字叫艾吉奥·奥迪托雷
When I was a young man.
在我年轻的时候
I had liberty, but I did not see it.
我曾拥有自由  却未曾看清其珍贵
I had time, but I did not know it.
我曾拥有时间 却茫然不知其意义
And I had love, but I did not feel it.
我曾拥有爱情 却从未感受其温度
It would be 41 years before I understood the meaning of all three.
四十一载光阴流逝  我才领悟这三者的真谛
I want to understand.
我想要弄明白
Like you do, to help my people.
然后就像你那样  去帮助我的百姓
I was an assassin for a long time, Yun.
我曾经做了很长一段时间的刺客  云
And I know that at any moment, someone could come for me.
我知道  随时都可能有人来找我寻仇
Or my family.
或是报复我的家人
Do you see? This is why I must to be careful.
你明白吗  所以我必须小心谨慎
I usually hire people to help me with vintage. The grape harvest.
通常我会雇人在丰收季节来帮忙摘葡萄
But...
不过…
Entra. Let's get something to eat.
不说这些了  我们去吃点东西吧
I would be lucky if this lasted three seasons.
如果这能维持三个季节就好了
This way. I want to show you something.
这边走  我给你看些东西
It is nice town!
这里不错吧
Piena di vita.
充满活力
Half of my family was murdered in this piazza.
我半个家族的人在这个广场被处刑
Right there, 45 years ago.
就在四十五年前的这里
But now, seeing like this, full of life.
但现在  你看看  一片繁荣
I can not help but feel contain.
我已经感到满足了
and satisfied that so much pain has faded away.
也渐渐淡忘了痛苦
The life of an assassin is pain, Yun.
刺客的一生是痛苦的  云
You suffer it, you inflict it.
你要受苦  抑或使别人痛苦
You watch it happen.
只能眼睁睁看着痛苦降临
If there is a hope, but you can't help it disappear in time.
但你却没法从这痛苦中逃离
Terrible irony, but there you go.
很讽刺吧  可事实就是如此
All right, time to drag this old man back to his villa.
好了  该把我这个老头送回庄园了
Yun, Andiamo! Hurry!
云  快离开这  快
It was my mentors wish to meet you.
本来是我师父要来找你的
We left China together, in secret. But these men...
我们偷偷离开中原  但是这些人…
They caught him in Venezia.
他们在威尼斯抓住了我师父
Who are they?
他们都是些什么人
Servants of the Emperor Jiajing.
都是嘉靖皇帝的手下
I was born a concubine. My mentor free me when I was younger.
我是妾室出身  是师父在我小时候把我救了出来
We returned later to save more girls,
后来我们想要回去解救更多的姑娘
but they were...
但她们都被…
The Emperor is a cruel man.
那狗皇帝心肠歹毒
He prefers "Ling Chi" to be heading.
比起斩首  他更喜欢用凌迟处死
Ling Chi?
凌迟
Slow process... many thousands cuts, then dead.
将身上的肉一片一片慢慢割下来  直到死亡
Pack some bags. You must stay Machiavelli's tonight.
赶紧收拾下  今晚你到马基雅维利家去
What happened?
发生什么了
A misunderstanding.
一个误解
Give me just a moment.
我这就去准备
When I fought the Borgia, revenge drove me forward.
在我对抗波奇亚家族的时候  复仇就是我的动力
And my first impulse was to aim for their head.
我第一反应就是砍掉他们的脑袋
In time, however.
但后来我发现
I learned that those inspire fear have more devoted followers than those who pray each love.
他们那些散播恐惧的人比我们这些宣扬真善美的人拥有更多的信徒
Killing Rodrigo and Cesare will ever accomplish nothing...
所以只干掉罗德里戈和凯撒是远远不够的…
without some equal measure of brotherhood.
必须要建立一个与他们实力相当的兄弟会
So, I spent many years to teach men and women think and act for themselves.
因此我花了很多年的时间教导人们  如何有自己的思想与作为
First in Roma, then Costantinopoli.
先是在罗马  然后是君士坦丁堡
Love binds our order together.
是爱  让我们紧紧地团结在一起
The love of people, of cultures, of the world.
是那些人与人  人与文化  人与世界的爱
Fight to preserve that which in inspires hope...
为了我们的信仰而去战斗
and you will win back people.
这样才能赢得人心
It will take a long time. Long time!
那需要很长时间
If you do it right, sì.
如果你的做法正确  那便是如此
Get some rest.
休息去吧
It's a long way home, you know.
回家的路很长
Much to see along the way.
这一路上我一定能学到很多
Thank you, mentor.
谢谢您  导师
Here.
拿着这个
This maybe useful one day.
说不定哪天会用得上
No, only if you lose you way.
不  等你迷失方向时再打开它
You should go.
一路保重
We'll be back just after dark.
我们会在天黑之前回来
You should have stayed at home.
你应该待在家里
I am home.
这就是我的家
We will be right over here.
我们去逛逛就回来
Il Diavolo! I hate this damn city.
该死的  我恨这个城市
I wish I was in Roma. I hear the women, there are...
我真希望现在是在罗马  听说那儿的女人…
like grape sangiovese wine, you know?
就像美酒一样  你懂吗
Not like here, Firenze.
不像这里  佛罗伦萨
I don't think Firenze is your problem.
我觉得你的问题不在于佛罗伦萨
Prego?
你刚说什么
Coraggio vecchio.
真是一名勇敢的老人家啊
Get some rest, huh?
好好歇着吧
When I was a young man.
在我年轻的时候
I had liberty, but I did not see it.
我曾拥有自由  却未曾看清其珍贵
I had time, but I did not know it.
我曾拥有时间  却茫然不知其意义
And I had love, but I did not feel it.
我曾拥有爱情  却从未感受其温度
Many decades would pass before I understood its meaning of all three.
数十载光阴流逝  我才领悟这三者的真谛
And now, in the twilight of my life,
如今  垂暮之年的我
this understanding has passed into contentment.
将这些领悟视为一笔财富
Love, liberty and time, once so disposable...
爱情  自由  时间  是它们教会了我
are the fuel that drive me forward.
如何指引自己前行
and love was the especially, mio caro.
而爱情尤为特别  亲爱的
For you, our children,
无论是你  还是我们的子孙
our brothers and sisters.
或是我们的兄弟姐妹
And for the vast and wonderful world that gave us life...
还有这个赐予我们生命的广袤世间
and keeps us guessing.
是如此令人捉摸不透
Endless affection, Mia Sofia.
致我挚爱的妻子  索菲亚
Forever yours... Ezio Auditore.
永远爱你的  艾吉奥·奥迪托雷